# **Benard Kipngeno**

#### Data Scientist

Address Nairobi, Kenya 00100

**Phone** 0797144246

**E-mail** benardkipngenoyegon@gmail.com

I am a highly motivated, adaptable, and meticulous Data Scientist with 3+ years of experience executing data- driven solutions to increase efficiency, accuracy, and utility of internal data processing. I am experienced in data analytics, creating statistical models, using predictive data modelling, and analyzing data to deliver insights and implement action-oriented solutions to complex business problems. ACHIEVEMENTS Done a lot of successful project at Upwork as a Freelancer, which enabled students in different Universities of the world to excel in their Course.

#### **Technical Profile**

- Microsoft Excel
- Tableau
- SPSS Statistics
- AWS Cloud Services
- STATA
- SQL
- ETL
- Microsoft Power BI
- R and Python

# **Competencies**

Training program development

Public speaking

Analytical and Critical Thinking

Teamwork and Collaboration

# **Work History**

2021-03 - Current

# Data Scientist/Analyst

University Of Nairobi, Nairobi

- Projects Done Machine learning predicting survival chances in Titanic using logistic regression in R
- Assessing impact of advertisement platforms on revenue using linear regression - Determining factors affecting systolic blood pressure using linear regression in SPSS

- Performed Project on Forecasting United States Unemployment rate using ARIMA model in STATA - Assessing risks in S&P 500 index stocks market using Capital Asset Pricing Method and ARIMA.
- Worked with stakeholders to develop quarterly roadmaps based on impact, effort and test coordinations.
- Utilized advanced querying, visualization and analytics tools to analyze and process complex data sets.
- Applied statistical and algebraic techniques to interpret key points from gathered data.
- Built company A/B testing frameworks to test model quality.
- Discovered stories told by data to present information to scientists and business managers.
- Developed polished visualizations to share results of data analyses.

#### 2021-03 - Current

#### **Data Analyst Trainer**

University of Nairobi, Nairobi

- Data Analysis with R programming trainer Introduction to Data Analysis and data science for beginners by covering data wrangling, data manipulation using Dplyr, data visualization using GGPLOT2 in integration with Plotly, descriptive and Inferential statistics, generating dynamic reports with R-Markdown
- Worked on predicting survival on Titanic using Titanic Dataset, using logistic regression
- Worked on sales revenue Dataset to determine best platform to invest in advertisements between
- YouTube, Magazine and Television
- Excel Trainer
- Conditional formatting
- Data Visualization
- Statistical Analysis using Data Analysis ToolPak
- H-LOOKUP, V-LOOKUP, Pivot tables
- Dashboards
- Data validation
- MySQL for data analysis
- Creating database schema containing different tables such as users' information, products purchased and distributors and producers of products
- Retrieving Data from multiple tables using multiple queries, views and procedures
- Integrating MySQL with Python using Py-mysql for analyzing queried data and Tableau for visualizing data obtained
- Manipulating and Analyzing data using
- SPSS data analysis trainer
- Entering Data in to SPSS software from questionnaire, importing data from different sources
- Data cleaning, management and merging data together
- Exploratory data analysis by performing descriptive statistics and inferential statistics including generating frequencies, measure of central tendencies and dispersion, and regression analysis
- Data Analysis trainer in STATA for Econometrics.

# **Education**

2018-01 - 2022-05 Bachelor of Science: Economics And Statistics

University of Nairobi - Kenya

- Awarded Second Class Honors Upper Division
- Member of Nairobi University Students' Statistics Association

#### **Certifications**

2023-02	Certified[AWS Cloud DevOps Engineer]- [November 2022 - March 2023]
2022-11	Certified [AWS Cloud Developer], [Udacity] - [July 2022- November 20222]
2022-10	Certified [Data Analyst], [DataCamp] - [May 2022- October 2022]
2023-10	Certified [Data Science], [DataCamp] - [September 2021- October 2022]